A can of soft drink and two large eggs may have a similar number of calories, but the eggs will provide us with protein, vitamins and other nutrients, and satisfy our hunger, while a fizzy drink provides little more than tooth decay and calories.
一罐软饮料和两个大鸡蛋可能含有相似数量的卡路里，但鸡蛋能为我们提供蛋白质、维生素和其他营养素，还解饿，而碳酸饮料除了导致蛀牙和卡路里之外几乎一无是处。
The important concept here is nutrient density.
这里重要的概念是营养密度。
This is the number of nutrients we take in for each calorie consumed.
这是指进食一卡路里食物所摄入的营养素数量。
No one would suggest replacing sweet drinks with eggs, but what can we do to increase nutrient density in our diet?
没有人会建议用鸡蛋代替甜饮料，但我们可以做些什么来增加饮食中的营养密度呢？
"Have you had your five a day?" that's the message on British supermarket shelves, and it's asking about fruit and vegetables.
"你今天吃到五份蔬果了吗？"这是英国超市货架上的信息，它是在询问水果和蔬菜的摄入情况。
Many countries have launched similar campaigns to encourage people to eat more healthily.
许多国家都发起了类似的活动，鼓励人们吃的更健康。
Fresh, natural produce is usually very dense in nutrients.
新鲜、天然的农产品通常营养密度很高。
Eating a wide range of fruits and vegetables is important, so some advice focuses on including different colours of food in our diets.
摄入多种多样的水果和蔬菜很重要，因此一些建议着重于在饮食中包含不同颜色的食物。"
'Eating a rainbow' could be one way to get more nutrients.
吃出一道彩虹"可能是获取更多营养素的一种方式。
Other advice recommends that we are more adventurous in what we eat.
其他建议则鼓励我们在饮食上更大胆尝试。
Cooking food that we haven't eaten before can lead us to use ingredients that we don't usually consume.
烹饪以前没吃过的食物可以让我们使用平时不常食用的食材。
This can give us a wider range of nutrients.
这能让我们获得更广泛的营养素。
It's not just about fruit and vegetables.
这不仅仅是水果和蔬菜的问题。
Even using different seasoning can offer health benefits.
即使是使用不同的调味料也能带来健康益处。
Nutrition academic Hazel Flight highlights that flavourings such as garlic, ginger or turmeric can have antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties, while also leading people to use less salt.
营养学学者黑兹尔·弗莱特强调，大蒜、生姜或姜黄等调味品具有抗氧化和抗炎的特性，同时还能让人们减少盐的用量。
Dairy products such as milk and cheese, are high in calcium, while in limited amounts, meat can be a good source of protein.
牛奶和奶酪等乳制品富含钙，而适量的肉类则是蛋白质的良好来源。
If you're not feeling that adventurous, then swapping individual food items can be beneficial.
如果你不太想冒险尝试，那么替换个别食物也是有益的。
Choosing wholegrain bread or rice instead of white bread or rice can increase fibre intake.
选择全麦面包或糙米代替白面包或白米饭可以增加纤维摄入量。
Unsalted nuts provide more nutrients than snacks such as crisps.
无盐坚果比薯片等零食提供更多的营养。
Possibly surprisingly, popcorn is a wholegrain snack that is high in fibre.
可能令人惊讶的是，爆米花是一种富含纤维的全谷物零食。
So, fresh fruit and vegetables, swapping the worst things, and just a little bit more adventure could be the secret to a more nutritious diet.
所以，新鲜的水果和蔬菜、替换掉营养价值低的食物，再加上一点点的冒险尝试，可能就是让饮食更有营养的秘诀。